hello in this video i will be going over
the main patterns you will find in the
game of minesweeper
and how they work being aware of the
recurring patterns
will stop you having to work out the
same logic multiple times
and will make solving the game quicker
and easier
in my opinion these are the main
patterns in the game that are useful to
start off learning
if you have come from my beginner's
guide video feel free to skip to the
timestamp of the ones that i have not
already explained
if you are just looking for answers to
all of these there is an imgur link in
the description for you
let's start with the three on the
straight
probably the most basic one that i would
even call a pattern
but since on a straight line like this
it can only be next to three cells
so you can always flag along the line
the one one and the two one are the two
fundamental patterns
so let's move on to those next for the
one one since the first two cells are
shared by both of the ones
the mind for the first one will always
satisfy the second one
so the third cell must always be free
note how this only works if there are no
other options
to the side of the first one
the two one pattern is fairly similar
for the two this one tells us that there
is one
mine in these two cells which only
leaves one space for the second mine
so you can always flag here because the
other mine must be in these two
this cell also has to be free
these last two are quite commonly found
but often don't progress too much on
their own
which is where it's useful to extend
them into the other patterns
the one two one is the most useful
pattern to look out for
and will quickly become your favorite
the only way to have two mines here
without putting two next to one of the
ones
is to have the mines on either side like
this
one two two one is another useful one
although seen less often than the one
two one in a way
this is a bit like two two one patterns
back to back
with the ones we know that there is only
one in these two cells
and one in these two cells so to
complete the twos
and not over satisfy the ones the flags
must be here
and here you can see how instead of
having to work out these two basic
patterns and put them together
knowing this pattern as its own thing
creates another shortcut to make things
easier
for the 1-1-1 pattern the mine must be
in the middle to satisfy
all of these ones if it was at either
edge
the one at the other side would not be
able to have a mine without putting two
minds next to the middle one
as an extension of the one one pattern
this again
doesn't apply when there are available
cells to the sides
as for the one one one one pattern
the only way to satisfy all of the ones
here
is if the mines are at both of the ends
again basically two one one patterns
so the role of having no more
constraints to the sides
still applies
i hope that you found this helpful if
any of these weren't clear to you
it can be useful to go back and see why
each one worked
i find trying out the other variations
and seeing why they don't
work can help clear things up
thanks for watching if you haven't
already do check out my larger guide
i do go on to expand on how you can use
these patterns more effectively
go watch that right now or go play
minesweeper on mysuper.online
or follow me on twitch at twitchtv.com
for some epic my super gameplay